[English subtitles are available]
[본 영상은 한글자막을 제공합니다]
[The Science of Falling in Love]
[이과생추입정망 : 사랑의 늪에 빠진 이과생]
[Episode 6]
[제6화]
Su Chengcheng
쑤청청 학생은
has been in our lab
개학하고부터 지금까지
for a while
우리 실험실에
since the beginning of the school year.
있었습니다
Today
오늘
according to
우리는
the practice of our lab,
실험실 관례대로
we will
투표를 통해
decide
쑤청청 학생이
whether she can continue to stay
실험실에 계속 남을지를
by voting.
결정하겠습니다
Didn't you say there would only be nine people?
9명이라면서요?
Pass them on.
건네주세요
Are the five votes of you still working?
그 5표는 쓸모 있는 거예요?
There are so many people.
사람들이 이렇게 많은데요
We usually only have nine.
평소에는 9명이었어
I don't know what's going on today, either.
오늘은 왜 이렇게 됐는지 나도 모르겠어
Then with so many people here, what should I do?
그럼 어떡해요?
It's fine. It's fine.
괜찮을 거야
Su Chengcheng.
쑤청청
How can you still think of whispering
이런 상황에서도
at this moment?
소곤거릴 기분이 드나 봐?
Is this funny to you?
재밌나 보지?
No.
아니에요
How about this?
이렇게 하자
Please come to the front.
너 여기 와서 서 있어
Just stand there.
거기에 서 있으면 돼
When I'm counting the votes,
이따가 내가 표를 읽을 테니까
you write them down.
네가 적도록 해
The voting officially begins.
투표를 시작하겠습니다
All the votes are collected.
투표 다 했지?
Now, I'll startthe counting.
표를 읽겠습니다
The first one is
첫 장
dissen…
반...
Affirmative.
찬성
Su Chengcheng has her own thinking,
쑤청청은 생각이 깊고
and can complete her assignment on time.
제때 임무를 완성하며
She does not follow others blindly,
무턱대고 따르지 않고
and she's also a good gamer.
게임도 잘합니다
The second one is affirmative.
두 번째 장, 찬성
Su Chengcheng is kind
쑤청청 학생은 착하고
and lively.
성격이 밝으며
She can often liven up
실험실의
the atmosphere of the lab
분위기 메이커로서
and cheer everyone up.
사람들을 즐겁게 해줍니다
In my opinion,
내 생각에는 말이야
we come to the lab
실험실에
to study
공부하러 왔고
and to complete our projects.
과제 하러 온 거지
We are not here to party,
파티하려고 온 게 아니잖아?
so what kind of atmosphere do we need to liven up?
무슨 분위기 메이커가 필요해?
And what kind of mood do we need to be cheered up?
굳이 사람들을 즐겁게 해줄 필요가 있나?
It's a dissenting vote. A dissenting vote.
반대, 반대표입니다
All Su Chengcheng thinks is romance.
쑤청청은 연애밖에 모르고
Her motivation to come to the lab is not pure.
실험실에 온 의도가 불순하며
She only thinks about relationships,
연애할 생각만 하고
and she's not capable,
능력이 부족하므로
so she's not suitable to stay in Brain and Intelligence.
뇌와 지능에 계속 남아있기에 부적절합니다
Affirmative. Dissenting. Dissenting.
찬성, 반대, 반대
Affirmative. Dissenting.
찬성, 반대
Su Chengcheng doesn't know
쑤청청은 실험실 기기들을
how to use many of the instruments.
사용할 줄 모릅니다
OK.
좋아
We've finished counting.
끝났다
Let's see the results.
결과를 봅시다
It's a tie.
찬성과 반대 반반입니다
Prof. Du, it's a tie.
교수님, 반반이래요
Well.
그러면...
How about you
이례적으로
make an exception and let me stay
일단 저를 실험실에 남겨두시고
for a couple of days so you can observe my performance?
며칠 관찰하시는 건 어떤가요?
Well...
그건...
How come you are so late?
왜 이제야 왔어?
Is Xiao Yuhe
샤오위허 학생만
the only one who hasn't voted yet?
아직 투표하지 않은 거 맞죠?
How about this?
그럼 이렇게 해요
Let's leave
결정권을
the casting vote to Xiao Yuhe.
샤오위허 학생한테 맡겨보죠
Xiao Yuhe.
샤오위허 학생
Tell us.
쑤청청 학생이
Do you agree with Su Chengcheng to stay
실험실에 남는 데 찬성해?
or leave?
아니면 떠났으면 좋겠어?
Prof. Du.
교수님
I'll leave.
제가 갈게요
You don't have to ask him.
샤오위허한테 부담 주지 마세요
Why are you leaving?
가긴 어딜 가?
What's the problem?
너 대체 왜 그래?
You have to carry everything through to the end.
시작과 끝을 분명하게 해야지
This isn't the end yet, is it?
아직 끝나지 않았잖아?
And Xiao Yuhe hasn't said anything, right?
샤오위허도 아직 투표 안 했잖아?
Stand up right
똑바로 서서
and listen to what Xiao Yuhe has to say.
샤오위허 얘기 들어봐
Go ahead.
얘기해
I agree with her to stay.
쑤청청을 남기는 데 찬성해요
So that's an affirmative vote, right?
찬성한다는 거야?
You are affirmative...
찬성한다면
Well, there has to be a reason.
찬성하는 이유가 필요해
Tell us your reasons.
이유를 말해봐
It is true that
객관적인 기준으로 봤을 때
her researching skills are not up to standard
쑤청청의 과학 연구 능력은
by objective standards.
분명 기준 미달입니다
However, she is only an undergraduate student
하지만 쑤청청은 아직 학부생이고
and is still in the process of learning the fundamentals.
기초 학습 과정에 있으므로
The specific competencies
구체적인 능력은
can be developed later.
앞으로 발전하면 됩니다
What I
그것보다
value more
전 쑤청청의
is her underlying driving mechanism,
기본 메커니즘을 더 중요하게 생각합니다
such as self-doubt, self-iteration,
스스로를 의심하고 발전하며
and curiosity,
호기심이 많은 점은
which was demonstrated
저와
when doing the romance experiment
연애 실험을 진행할 때
with me.
나타났습니다
Besides, when I asked her
그리고 쑤청청더러
to clean the electrode caps,
전극 모자를 정리하라고 했는데
she not only cleaned it
정리뿐만 아니라
but also sorted
해당 기자재들을
all the relevant equipment.
다 분류해놨더군요
Moreover,
또 하나는 쑤청청은 졘밍을 대할 때
she's quite patient with Jianming.
인내심이 강했습니다
Patience is the most important quality in researching.
이 점은 과학 연구에서 가장 중요한 부분입니다
So I decide to let her stay.
그래서 쑤청청이 실험실에 남아있기를 바랍니다
The result is out.
결과가 나왔네요
The meeting is over.
이만합시다
I want a cup of bubble tea with half sugar.
밀크티 마실 거야, 당도는 50퍼센트
OK.
네
3, 2, 1.
셋, 둘, 하나
♫A secret has made a decision.♫
♫ 비밀 하나에 대해 결정을 내렸어 ♫
♫Tonight, tonight.♫
♫ 오늘 밤 ♫
♫Respond to your sincerity with my heart,♫
♫ 너의 진심에 내 마음으로 보답하기로 했어 ♫
♫Alright, alright.♫
♫ 좋아 ♫
♫No matter how far it is,♫
♫ 아무리 멀어도 ♫
♫Working harder and getting closer.♫
♫ 노력할 수록 더 가까이 다가가 ♫
♫My dream, my dream. Hey.♫
♫ 내 꿈 ♫
♫Meeting you in my youth,♫
♫ 젊은 청춘 너와의 만남 ♫
♫Planting our promise,♫
♫ 우리의 약속을 심어둬 ♫
♫My dream, my dream. Hey.♫
♫ 내 꿈 ♫
♫You support me with your eyes,♫
♫ 너의 눈빛에서 용기를 얻고 ♫
♫I'm little but I'm brave to try.♫
♫ 작은 나는 용감하게 부딪혀 ♫
♫With the best of me,♫
♫ 제일 아름다운 모습으로 ♫
♫To the prettiest place,♫
♫ 제일 아름다운 곳으로 갈 거야 ♫
♫I want to live in your heart.♫
♫ 너의 마음속에 들어갈 거야 ♫
♫Promise me we'll bloom together.♫
♫ 우리 같이 피어나기로 약속해 ♫
♫Yes OK. Yes OK. Let's go.♫
♫ 좋아 출발해 ♫
Cheers.
건배
Now this is the only difficult point,
지금 이게 난제입니다
I think that for the students to grasp it now, it's…
학생들이 지금 파악한...
Come in.
들어오세요
Ms. Chen,
학장님
you've come back from the academic conference?
학술회의에서 돌아오셨네요
Yes.
그래요
Prof. Du, these are the papers you asked for.
교수님께서 달라고 하셨던 문헌 자료입니다
Then I'll leave.
이만 가볼게요
Wait.
잠깐만
I have something to talk with you.
너한테 할 얘기 있어
Tell me.
얘기해 봐
Why did you let
왜 쑤청청을
Su Chengcheng stay?
남겨둔 거야?
I said my reasons earlier.
저번에 말씀드렸잖아요
You call those reasons?
그걸 이유라고 해?
If feeding the monkey well
원숭이에게 먹이를 잘 준 것도
counts as a sign of competence,
능력이라는 거야?
then, according to your logic,
그러면
we should recruit more zoo keepers
앞으로 실험실에서 모집할 때
for our lab
동물원 사육사를
in the future.
모집할까?
I'm fine with that.
전 괜찮은데요
It's up to you.
교수님의 의견이 중요하죠
Go, go, go. Hurry and leave.
빨리 나가
Ms. Chen,
천 학장님
I'm having a headache over this.
쑤청청 일 때문에 골치가 아픕니다
I found that
제가 보니까
since he met Su Chengcheng,
샤오위허가 쑤청청을 만나고부터
he's become abnormal.
점점 이상해지고 있습니다
He is getting stupider every day.
점점 멍청해지는 것 같아요
He stood just like he did a moment ago.
아까처럼 멍하니 서서
Just like this.
이렇게 웃기만 하더군요
Su Chengcheng?
쑤청청이란 학생
Is she pretty?
예뻐요?
No, she isn't.
안 예뻐요
No, wait,
그게 아니라...
Ms. Chen,
천 학장님
what did you just say?
방금 뭐라고 하셨어요?
I asked you if she's pretty.
쑤청청 학생 예쁜가요?
You've met her.
학장님께서도 만나보셨을 겁니다
She's the girl
전에 샤오위허랑
who did the romance experiment
연애 실험하던
with Xiao Yuhe.
그 여자애예요
She's that girl.
그 여자애예요?
Yes.
네, 맞아요
I think she's pretty.
되게 예쁘던데요?
Then this romance experiment
연애 실험이
is getting interesting.
참 흥미로워지는군요
Chengcheng.
청청
Say, why did Xiao Yuhe
샤오위허가 결국
vote for you to stay
찬성표를 던졌던데
in the end?
무슨 이유일까?
How shouldI know?
나도 몰라
His mind is so difficult to guess.
샤오위허가 무슨 생각하는지 모르겠어
Say,
설마
could it be that
샤오위허가
he still sees me as a tool
아직도 날 도구로 생각하는 걸까?
and is secretly
몰래
trying to do that experiment again?
나를 실험에 이용하려고?
Then ask him.
가서 물어봐
I don't want to.
싫어
Look,
너
you have to stay in this lab
적어도 그 실험실에서
at least until finishing your graduation project in your senior year, right?
대학교 4학년 졸업 논문 끝날 때까지 있어야 하잖아
You have to get along with him
그렇게 긴 시간 동안
for such a long time.
마주쳐야 할 텐데
I think that for a lot of things,
많은 건
it's better to ask him for clarification.
제대로 물어보는 게 좋을 것 같아
I'm with Xiaomeng.
샤오멍의 말이 맞는 것 같아
You should ask him.
가서 물어봐
Ask him.
물어봐
No.
싫어
To get things clear.
제대로 알아봐
Do it.
얼른
[Xiao Yuhe]
[샤오위허]
Why did you want me
왜 날
to stay in the lab?
실험실에 남겨둔 거예요?
Do you
선배 혹시
have other experiments to do
다른 실험 때문에
and want me to
절 실험용으로
continue being your subject?
쓰려고 그러는 거죠?
He replied.
답장 왔어
What did he say?
뭐라고 했어?
Let me see.
보여줘
He recalled it.
메시지를 취소했네
What did he say?
방금 뭐라고 했어?
"No."
'아니'
Just a message with two letters?
그렇게 두 글자만 보냈어?
What's the point of recalling it?
그런데 왜 취소한 거야?
He's typing.
지금 입력 중이야
See what he sent.
뭐라고 하는지 기다려보자
"No."
'아니'
What does this mean?
무슨 뜻이지?
Beats me.
나도 몰라
Told you.
내가 말했잖아
His mind is hard to guess.
샤오위허가 무슨 생각하는지 알 수 없다고
Chengcheng.
청청
Maybe Xiao Yuhe doesn't hate you.
샤오위허가 널 싫어하는 게 아닐 수도 있어
Then, how about we watch a movie
그럼 우리 저녁에 밥 먹고
after dinner?
영화 보러 가자
You bet.
당연히 가야지
As long as you are happy.
우리 자기가 좋다면 됐어
Great.
좋아
Our Jiaze is great.
우리 쟈쩌 너무 착해
Senior Jiaze.
쟈쩌 선배
You are...?
누구더라?
You don't remember me?
저 기억 안 나세요?
I asked you
지난번 선배가 참가하셨던
several questions
포럼에서
in your last forum,
제가 선배한테 많은 질문을 했었잖아요
and you answered them all at that time.
그때 선배가 다 대답해주셨어요
Don't mention it.
별거 아니니까
Just a piece of cake.
신경 쓰지 마
They were a piece of cake for you,
선배한테는 별거 아니겠지만
but for me,
저는 덕분에
your answers have enlightened me a lot.
큰 깨달음을 얻었어요
I've been trying to find an opportunity
선배한테
to thank you
감사하단 말씀 드리고 싶었는데
but haven't found one yet.
기회가 없었어요
I just bought a cup of milk tea,
저 아까 밀크티 샀는데
which I haven't opened yet,
아직 포장을 뜯지 않았어요
and I've heard that it's a hit on the Internet.
왕훙 밀크티라고 하던데
If you don't mind,
괜찮으시다면
I will give it to you.
밀크티 드릴게요
No, no, you don't have to.
됐어
-Just take it. -Really, you don't have to.
- 꼭 받으세요 - 됐어
Senior Jiaze, you...
선배...
You...
이거...
What have you done?
대체 뭐 하는 거야?
I...
저...
Senior Jiaze, I'm sorry, I...
선배, 죄송해요
-I... I didn't mean it, I... -Tissue papers, do you have tissue papers?
- 제, 제가 실수로... - 휴지 있어?
I don't.
없어
Do you have any?
휴지 있어?
-Me... Me either. -What’s wrong with you.
- 저한테도 없어요 - 대체 뭐 하는 거예요?
I'm really sorry, I...
죄송합니다
I've got a class.
수업 보러 가야 해서
I have to go.
먼저 갈게요
Senior Jiaze, please get some tissue papers and clean it with them.
선배, 휴지 찾아서 닦으세요
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
죄송합니다
What's the problem with this guy?
저 사람 대체 뭐야?
Let's go.
가자
Let's head to that restroom
일단 화장실로 가서
-and clean it up. -What’s wrong?
- 닦자 - 대체 왜 이런 거야?
Why does he always have trouble with milk tea?
왜 맨날 밀크티 가지고 저래?
Why is he so annoying?
저 사람 진짜 싫어
So disgusting.
진짜 싫어
Don't let me see him again.
다시는 마주치지 말았으면 좋겠어
Yeah.
그러게
You look so clean and nice,
멀쩡하게 생겨서
but why are you so obnoxious?
사람이 왜 그렇게 못됐어?
When you see a guy you like,
마음에 드는 남자라고 해서
will you just try to get close to him?
그렇게 들이대도 되는거야?
I have modified
소스 코드를
this source code remotely,
원격 작업으로 수정했어
please check again.
한 번 더 검사해봐
OK.
알았어요
Why are you playing games all day?
왜 맨날 게임을 해?
What do you think about Su Chengcheng?
쑤청청 어떻게 생각해?
What do you mean?
뭐가?
I think she's nice.
괜찮은 것 같은데?
Haven't I already said that
내가 말했잖아
although her scientific research ability is not strong,
쑤청청은 과학 연구 능력이 부족하지만
what I value
난
is her underlying ability?
쑤청청의 기본 능력을 좋게 봐
I think she's nice,
쑤청청은 괜찮은 애인 것 같아
because she plays games for me in the morning.
아침에 나 대신 게임 해줬거든
What are you talking about?
그런데 너 방금 뭐라고 했어?
See, Anipop
이 퍼즐게임처럼
seems easy,
쉬워 보여도
but
사실은
even if you understand its algorithm,
계산법을 알아도
you'll never know
다음에
what critter
어떤 동물 그림이
it will drop next.
뜰지 몰라
It's full of surprise.
모든 게 예상 밖이지
I think that
난
Su Chengcheng
쑤청청이
is a surprise like it.
예상 밖의 인물이라고 생각해
But maybe she's the kind of surprise that makes you happy.
서프라이즈일 수도 있어
You.
너...
Senior Yuhe,
샤오 선배
it seems that
이 부분이
this part still has problems.
아직도 문제인 것 같아요
It keeps popping weird letters.
이상한 알파벳이 계속 떠요
OK.
알았어
I'll go to the lab and take a look.
실험실에 가볼게
Unbelievable.
믿기지 않아
Let me tell you, you can't trust
셰샤오멍의 말을
Xie Xiaomeng's words entirely.
다 믿을 건 못돼
Xiao Yuhe has something wrong
샤오위허는 머리가
with this part of his,
좀 이상해
and you can't interpret him
일반적인 논리로
with the logic of normal people.
생각하면 안 되지
Chengcheng, I'm looking for you.
청청, 널 찾는 중이었어
Ms. Chen said that
학장님께서
there was a mission for you.
너에게 줄 임무가 있다고 하셔
has a mission
나한테
for me?
임무를 주신다고?
By the way,
참
she asked you to go with Xiao Yuhe.
샤오위허랑 같이 오라고 하셨어
Your senior
두 학생의 선배가
has to come with me for an urgent meeting
나랑 같이 긴급회의에 가야 하는데
and the family baby-sitter is off today,
베이비 시터가 오늘 휴가라서
so the kids are unattended.
아이를 봐줄 사람이 없어요
This important task
두 사람한테
is entrusted to  two of you
이 중요한 임무를 맡길게요
and I believe that you will do a good job.
두 사람이 잘 해낼 거라 믿어요
Thank you.
고마워요
Let's switch places.
자리 바꿀까?
Ms. Chen.
천 학장님
I'm sorry to interrupt you,
죄송해요
but I still
물어볼 게
can't figure out
하나
one thing.
있어서요
Go ahead.
학장님은
Why did you
왜
have to assign
두 사람에게
this mission to them
그런 임무를 맡기셨나요?
and insist that Su Chengcheng
왜 굳이 쑤청청더러
go with him?
샤오위허랑 같이 가게 하셨어요?
I think that you are kind of wasting
샤오위허 학생의
Xiao Yuhe's time.
시간을 낭비하신 것 같은데요
In my opinion,
제 생각에는요
Xiao Yuhe's time for experiments
샤오위허 학생의 실험 시간은
is quite precious.
아주 중요하답니다
Du,
두 교수님
have you ever heard of assists?
이런 걸 '어시스트'라고 해요, 혹시 아세요?
In soccer.
축구
Volley ball.
배구
Basketball?
농구... 뭐 그런 건가요?
Du, really?
설마... 두 교수님
H-how come you know nothing about
요즘 유행에 대해
the modern pop cultures?
전혀 모르시네요
What's that?
뭐죠?
You really know nothing?
정말 모르시네요
See, Du.
두 교수님
When you have time,
한가하실 때
you should talk more
젊은이들과
with young people.
얘기 좀 나눠보세요
You can't
시대에
fall behind the times.
뒤떨어지면 안 되죠
Yuhe,
샤오
thank you so much for today.
오늘 정말 고마워
I've just been informed by Ms. Chen
방금 학장님의 통지를 받고
that we'll be leaving for Shanghai on a business trip immediately.
곧 상하이로 출장 가야 하는데
The kids' father
애 아빠가
has to work late today
오늘 야근이라서
and won't be back until after 10,
저녁 10시가 넘어서 돌아온대
so I'll have to ask you
그래서 너희 두 사람에게
to take care of them for a little while.
부탁해야겠어
Their father will come to pick them up as soon as he gets off work.
애 아빠가 퇴근하면 곧장 올 거야
OK, senior.
알았어요, 선배
Senior, don't worry.
선배, 걱정하지 마세요
It's fine.
괜찮아요
You can count on us
아이를 저희에게 맡기면
to take good care of the kids.
잘 돌볼게요
That's great.
잘됐어
There are their cups,
여기에 아이의 물컵이랑
snacks,
간식
and some toys in here.
장난감이 들어있어
Got it.
알았어요
I really have to go.
늦기 전에 빨리 가봐야 해
I'll leave Dali and Xiaoli in your hands.
다리랑 샤오리는 두 사람에게 맡길게
OK.
알았어요
OK, I'll go.
그럼 이만 갈게
I have to pack my luggage.
짐 정리하러 가야 해
Bye-bye.
갈게
Contact me if you have any questions.
문제 있으면 제때 연락해
-Alright? -OK.
- 알겠지? - 네
Good. Bye-bye. Bye-bye.
갈게
The basic score is 10.
기초점수 10점
3 combos. 3 times 10.
3번 연속 제거, 3 곱하기 10
The base is N.
기수 N
The multiplier is M.
배수 M
Hello?
여보세요
The door won't open?
문이 안 열려요?
Please wait a minute.
잠시만요
I'll go downstairs and get it immediately.
제가 내려갈게요
Hello, your takeout.
안녕하세요, 택배 도착했습니다
-Thank you. -You're welcome.
- 고마워요 - 아니에요
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
죄송해요
Senior Xixi?
시시 선배
Gu Chen, why are you here?
구천, 너 왜 여기 있어?
I'm...
저 지금...
Take care on your way out.
그럼 잘 가
You look so pretty.
예쁘네
Let's pick a hair clip.
머리핀 하나 골라볼까?
Isn't the watermelon hair clip pretty?
수박 머리핀, 예쁘지?
Dali, how about we give your little sister
다리, 여동생한테
this watermelon hair clip?
수박 머리핀 달아줄까?
It's ugly.
안 예뻐요
The watermelon hair clip is lame.
수박 머리핀은 촌스러워요
Mom always gives me
엄마는 평소 저한테
the strawberry hair clip.
딸기 머리핀을 달아주셨어요
Is it lame?
촌스럽다고?
We don't have any strawberry hair clips,
딸기 머리핀 없어
so let's just use this watermelon one.
수박 머리핀 달자
It's so pretty.
얼마나 예뻐?
I don't want the watermelon.
수박 싫어요
I want the strawberry.
난 딸기가 좋아요
How about we pick another one?
그러면 다른 걸 골라보자
What's so ugly about this one?
뭐가 안 예쁜데?
Isn't it pretty? Here.
되게 예쁘잖아, 가져
I don't want it. I don't want it. I don't want it.
싫어요
She doesn't want it.
싫다잖아
The watermelon hair clip is beautiful.
수박 머리핀은 아주 예뻐
It looks best on Brother Xiao Yuhe.
샤오위허 오빠 머리에 달면 아주 예쁠 거야
Ask him to try it on.
한 번 달아볼까?
Right.
맞아
Why don't you try it on?
네 머리에 달지 그래?
It's just for coaxing the kid.
애를 구슬려야 하잖아
See how pretty it is.
얼마나 예뻐
Do you want it?
너한테도 달아줘?
If you don't,
네가 싫다면
I'll give it to him.
오빠한테 줄 거야
No, I want the watermelon hair clip.
안 돼요, 난 수박 머리핀이 좋아요
I'm the prettiest one wearing it.
내 머리에 달아야 제일 예뻐요
You're the prettiest one wearing it.
그럼, 네 머리에 달아야 제일 예쁘지
Then hurry and give it back to us.
얼른 돌려줘
Here you are.
자
Let's wear it now
얼른 머리에 달자
so no one can snatch it from us.
다른 사람이 빼앗아 가기 전에
Boring.
지루해
Let me see.
내가 봐줄까?
You are the prettiest one wearing it.
네 머리에 다니까 제일 예쁘네
You look so good.
너무 예뻐
A Rubik's Cube.
루빅큐브네
Let's wear another one on this side.
이쪽에도 하나 달자
It's done.
다 됐어
Brother,
형
can you teach me?
저 좀 가르쳐주실 수 있나요?
Of course.
그럼
Wash your hands.
손 씻자
Wash your hands and make the gifts.
손 다 씻은 뒤에 선물을 만들자
Have you made up your mind
엄마한테
on what to make for your mom?
무슨 선물을 드릴지 생각했어?
Senior Yuhe,
샤오 선배
the model we made before
저희가 전에 만들던 모형
has been reporting data errors.
데이터가 계속 오류로 뜨네요
Could you go there and take a look?
지금 확인해볼 수 있어요?
I need to go, call me if you need anything.
일 보러 갈 테니까 일 있으면 불러
OK.
알았어
This hand is clean.
이 손마저 씻으면
Both of the paws are clean.
두 손이 깨끗해지지
1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6, 7.
하나, 둘, 셋, 넷, 다섯, 여섯, 일곱
Done. All clean.
좋아, 깨끗해졌어
Come with your big brother.
오빠랑 같이 가자
Dali.
다리
Ms. Chen is the only one
천 학장님 사무실 비밀번호는
who knows the password of her office.
천 학장님만 아셔
The problem is that she and our senior
그런데 천 학장님과 선배가
have gone to a confidential meeting in Shanghai
지금 상하이에 비밀 회의하러 갔어
and are on the plane right now,
지금 비행기에 있어서
so we can't reach her by phone.
연락 안 돼
I think it will be a few more hours
천 학장님한테 연락하려면
before we can get through to her.
몇 시간 후에야 가능할 거야
It's so dark. I'm afraid of the dark.
너무 어두워요, 무서워요
Chengcheng, where are you going?
청청, 어디 가?
Dali, don't cry.
다리, 울지 마
I'll find a way to get you out.
형이 널 구해줄 거야
Come on, Dongmao, move a bit.
자, 동마오, 비켜줘
No.
안 돼
It's too dangerous for a kid
어린애가 저기 혼자 있는 거
to be alone in there.
너무 위험해
I'll remove the door.
이 문을 따야 해
Let me see.
제가 한번 볼게요
Wait, do you know the password?
비밀번호 알아?
I have a rough idea
학장님이 비밀번호를 설정하시는
of the pattern of Ms. Chen's password setting.
룰을 알고 있어요
Well,
그게...
if you make three wrong entries,
3번 잘못 입력하면
it will automatically lock from the inside.
문이 자동으로 잠기게 돼요
But we have to try, right?
그래도 시도는 해봐야지
Go ahead, go ahead.
알겠어요, 시도해봐요
It's so dark. I'm afraid of the dark.
너무 어두워요, 무서워요
Don't be afraid. Miss Chengcheng is coming.
무서워하지 마, 누나가 갈게
It's unlocked.
잠금 해제되었습니다
Come here, Dali.
자, 다리
It's alright now.
괜찮아
The windows in this room are sealed.
이 방의 창문은 안 열리는 거예요
There's none.
없어요
I just wanted to take this
이걸 엄마한테
as a gift for Mom.
선물로 드리고 싶었을 뿐이에요
It's fine. It's fine.
괜찮아
Chengcheng.
청청
Don't look down. Don't look down.
아래를 보지 마
Yuhe is coming.
샤오가 갈 거야
No, no, no.
괜찮아
Yuhe is coming to save you.
샤오위허가 널 구해줄 거야
Yuhe is here.
샤오위허 여기 있어
Come here.
이리 와
It's too high.
너무 높아요
I haven't noticed it when coming.
올 때는 몰랐는데
Now I can't get across.
이젠 가지 못하겠어요
D-don't stand on the edge.
거기 서 있지 마요
-It's too dangerous. -Come over, I'll catch you.
- 너무 위험해요 - 내가 잡아줄게, 이쪽으로 와
Hey, Yuhe.
아니, 샤오위허
How about you two come down first and then hug?
일단 내려와서 안는 건 어때?
Be careful. Be careful.
조심해
Come here, be slow.
자, 천천히 내려가
Be slow. Be slow.
천천히
It's all my fault today.
오늘은 다 내 잘못이었어요
I didn't keep an eye on Dali.
다리를 잘 돌보지 못했어요
I let him stay by himself in that small dark room
다리를 캄캄한 방에
for such a long time.
오랫동안 혼자 내버려 둬서
He must be scared.
엄청 무서웠을 거예요
Aren't you quick to step up
너도 빨리 나와서
and protect them?
애들을 지켜줬잖아
You have done well.
너도 잘 했어
Let me make them a gift.
애들한테 선물을 만들어줄 거예요
I'll give it to them when they wake up.
애들이 깨어나면 선물 줘야지
How did you know
내가 플래시를 그릴 거란 걸
I want to draw a flashlight?
어떻게 알았어요?
How come you know how to make this?
선배가 어떻게 이런 걸 할 줄 알아요?
I've read about it
예전에 잡지에서
in a magazine before.
본 적이 있어
What magazine?
무슨 잡지요?
Only a few people know how to make this.
할 줄 아는 사람 얼마 안 될 텐데요
It's been a long time.
오래전 일이라서
I don't remember.
나도 기억 안 나
Could it be that someone has taught you how to do it?
누가 선배한테 가르쳐줬어요?
Have we met before?
혹시 우리 예전에 만났던 적 있어요?
Haven't you said that
네가
if you ever met me before,
날 만난 적이 있었으면
you definitely would have recognized me?
날 알아볼 거라고 했잖아
I'm sure we never met before.
우린 만난 적이 없었을 거야
This toy
이 장난감은
is called the Amazing Flashlight.
신기한 플래시라고 하는데
It's made by this mister.
이 형아가 너희들을 위해 만든 거야
See,
이것 봐
put in this flashlight,
플래시를 넣으면
and the light will come out.
빛이 들어오게 돼
I played with this too when I was little.
누나도 어렸을 때 이거 놀았었어
It's yours.
너희들에게 선물할게
Quick.
얼른
-Dali, you take it. -Hold it.
- 오빠가 가지고 있어 - 가져가
Then you'll not be afraid of the dark.
이젠 어두운 곳에서도 두렵지 않겠네
Thank you, miss.
고마워요, 누나
Thank you for your effort today.
오늘 수고 많으셨어요
It's fine.
아니에요
We like them a lot as well.
저희도 아이들과 즐거웠어요
Mr. Xiao Yuhe.
샤오위허 형
This is for you and Miss Chengcheng.
형이랑 청청 누나한테 주는 선물이에요
Thanks.
고마워
Alright.
됐어
Say goodbye to the mister and miss.
이젠 형이랑 누나랑 안녕해야지
Let's go home.
집에 가자
Bye-bye.
안녕히 계세요
-Goodbye. -Bye-bye.
- 안녕 - 안녕히 계세요
Bye-bye.
안녕
Thank you. Thank you. Let's go.
고마워요, 가자
Senior, there's a cut on your hand.
선배, 손 다치셨네요
If you say that later,
조금만 더 늦게 말했으면
it will heal.
상처가 다 아물었겠다
Thank you for voting me
오늘
today.
저한테 투표해주셔서 고마웠어요
Don't mention it.
아니야
Why did you let me stay?
왜 절 실험실에 남겨둔 거예요?
Haven't I said this
투표할 때
when voting?
얘기했잖아
You have strong emotional perception
넌 공감 능력이 강한 애라고
and fair technical skills,
기술력도 괜찮고
which will be useful in future work.
앞으로 쓸모 있을 거야
You complemented me.
절 칭찬해주셨네요
Take this.
이건 네가 가져
You have the most credit today.
오늘은 다 네 덕분이었으니까
Thank you for your effort.
수고 많았어
Su Chengcheng. Su Chengcheng.
쑤청청
Zhu Panpan, is that you?
주판판, 너야?
Zhu Panpan?
주판판
Yes, it's me.
나 맞아
Su Chengcheng,
쑤청청
why is your homeso dark?
너희 집 왜 이렇게 어두워?
Dad has suddenly fallen ill
아빠가 갑자기 아프셔서
and Mom is taking him to the hospital.
엄마랑 같이 병원에 가셨어
Now the power is out.
지금은 또 정전돼서
It's dark here. I'm scared.
너무 어두워, 나 너무 무서워
How did you know
내가 플래시 그릴 거란 걸
I want to draw a flashlight?
어떻게 알았어요?
I've read about it
예전에 한 잡지에서
in a magazine before.
본 적이 있어
I was afraid of the dark
어렸을 때
when I was a kid,
난 어둠을 두려워했다
and he conjured up the Amazing Flashlight.
그 애는 신기한 플래시를 꺼내 들었다
It lights up. It really does.
정말 밝아졌어
It's amazing.
너무 신기해
It lit up my room,
그 애는 내 방을 밝혀주었고
and also my life.
내 삶도 밝혀주었다
You drew so well.
진짜 잘 그렸네
♫The more we get together,♫
♫ 우리 함께 있자 ♫
Su Chengcheng,
쑤청청
do you not know this one?
이 문제 풀 줄 몰라?
Let me explain it to you.
내가 설명해줄게
♫Together, together.♫
♫ 함께 있자 ♫
From now on, we can solve any questions
네가 모르는 문제 있으면
that you don't know the answer to together.
우리 같이 해결하자
Let's solve them together in the future.
앞으로는 다 같이 해결하자
♫The more we get together,♫
♫ 우리 함께 있자 ♫
6, 7.
육, 칠
Are you still not understanding it?
아직도 이해 안 돼?
He would go to great lengths
그 애는 인내심 있게
♫The happier we'll be.♫
♫ 그러면 엄청 즐거울 거야 ♫
to explain all the math problems to me
모든 수학 문제를 설명해주었다
and would share his favourite things
그 애는 제일 좋아하는 물건도
with me.
나랑 공유했다
It’s really 16.
정말 16개구나
Where did you buy these?
어디서 샀어?
I want a set, too.
나도 사야겠어
♫For your friends are my friends,♫
♫ 네 친구는 내 친구고 ♫
It was a gift from my dad
이건 내가 어렸을 때
when I was little.
아빠가 선물해주신 거야
♫And my friends are your friends.♫
♫ 내 친구는 네 친구이니까 ♫
Then you must like it so much.
그럼 네가 애지중지하는 거겠네
This is for you.
이걸 줄게
♫The more we get together,♫
♫ 우리 함께 있자 ♫
Take it and you'll also be
이거 받으면
my best, best friend.
너도 나의 가장 친한 친구가 되는 거야
♫The happier we'll be.♫
♫ 그러면 엄청 즐거울 거야 ♫
Since being friends with him,
그 애랑 친구가 된 후로
we have planned countless things
우리는 앞으로
that we'll do together in the future.
앞으로 같이 해야 할 많은 일들을 계획했다
Until...
그러던 어느 날
♫The more we get together,♫
♫ 우리 함께 있자 ♫
♫Together, together,♫
♫ 함께 있자 ♫
♫The happier we'll be.♫
♫ 그러면 엄청 즐거울 거야 ♫
♫For your friends are my friends,♫
♫ 네 친구는 내 친구고 ♫
♫And my friends are your friends.♫
♫ 내 친구는 네 친구이니까 ♫
♫The more we get together,♫
♫ 우리 함께 있자 ♫
♫The happier we'll be.♫
♫ 그러면 엄청 즐거울 거야 ♫
Miss,
선생님
why didn't Zhu Panpan come to school today?
오늘 주판판이 왜 학교에 안 나왔어요?
Zhu Panpan?
주판판은
He has transferred to another school
다른 학교에
to study elsewhere.
전학 갔어
He has transferred to another school?
전학 갔다고?
Why didn't he tell me
이렇게 중요한 일을
about such a big thing?
나한테 얘기하지 않았다니
I ran to his house
주판판네 집에 가서
and wanted to ask him.
물어보려 했는데
But I found that
주판판네 가족은
it was already empty.
이사 가고 없었다
Zhu Panpan. Zhu Panpan.
주판판
Zhu Panpan, are you still home?
주판판, 집에 있어?
Zhu Panpan, come out.
주판판, 나와
Zhu Panpan. Zhu Panpan.
주판판
Zhu Panpan. Hurry and get out.
주판판, 나오라고
Hurry up and get out.
얼른 나와줘
Su Chengcheng. It's already late.
쑤청청, 늦었으니까
Let's go home.
집에 돌아가자
No.
싫어
Zhu Panpan will definitely come back.
주판판은 분명 돌아올 거야
I'm going to show him
주판판에게
my sticks.
내 장난감 막대기를 보여줘야 하거든
Su Chengcheng, don't cry.
쑤청청, 울지 마
Zhu Panpan left without telling you.
주판판이 너에게 전학 가는 걸 얘기하지 않은 걸 보니
He didn't see you as his friend at all.
널 친구로 생각하지 않은 거야
Maybe
어쩌면
he just had something
주판판은 일이 있어서
that took him away temporarily for a few days;
며칠 동안 돌아오지 않은 걸 수도 있고
maybe
어쩌면
he was delayed by something
주판판이 집으로 돌아오는 길에
on the way back;
무슨 일 때문에 못 돌아온 걸 수도 있고
maybe...
어쩌면...
Although he left without saying goodbye,
주판판은 말도 없이 떠나갔지만
I didn't give up.
난 포기하지 않고
I kept writing emails to him,
매일 주판판에게 메일을 보냈다
expecting
난 주판판의 답장을
to hear from him one day.
기다렸다
But after all these years have passed,
하지만 몇 해가 지나도
those emails all went unanswered.
나는 주판판의 답장을 받지 못했다
I finally had to come to terms with that
난 그제야
all those years of missing
그동안의 그리움이
were just a one-man show for me.
나 혼자만의 것임을 알게 되었다
Those fond memories of the past
과거의 아름다운 추억은
had become evidence of my naivety.
유치한 것들일 뿐이었다
So I decided to
그래서 난 그 추억을
delete them all.
모두 지웠다
It's as if forgetting Zhu Panpan
주판판을 잊으면
could erase myself
외로움을 두려워하던 나를
that was afraid of loneliness.
잊을 수 있을 것 같아서
This is for you.
이거 줄게
Take it and you'll also be
이거 받으면
my best, best friend.
너도 나의 가장 친한 친구가 되는 거야
Zhu Panpan, is that you?
주판판, 너야?
Yes, it's me.
나 맞아